{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "The most common device used for measuring air speed is __________",
        "answers": {
          "a": "Altimeter",
          "b": "Thermometer",
          "c": "Pressure gauge",
          "d": "Pitot tube"
        },
        
        "correctAnswer": "d",
        "difficulty": "beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "The randomness of the molecules gives us ________ pressure",
        "answers": {
          "a": "Stagnation",
          "b": "Static",
          "c": "Dynamic",
          "d": "Absolute"
        },
       
        "correctAnswer": "b",
        "difficulty": "beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"How does the pitot tube help in measuring the airspeed?",
        "answers":{
          "a": "Using temperature",
          "b": "Using velocity",
          "c": "Using mach number",
          "d": "Using the pressure difference"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"d",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"The instrument which combines both the static and total pressure is _______5",
        "answers":{
          "a":"Dynamic probe",
          "b": "Static probe",
          "c": "Pitot static probe",
          "d": "Stagnation probe"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"c",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question": "The dynamic pressure can be used in all flows from incompressible to hypersonic.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"The dynamic pressure can be given by ____________",
        "answers":{
          "a":"difference of total and static pressure",
          "b":"sum of total and static pressure",
          "c":"product of total and static pressure",
          "d": "double of total and static pressure"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"The pressure difference (p0-p1) holds good only for incompressible flow.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"True",
          "b":"False"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"a",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"When the local flow velocity is zero itself then _________.",
        "answers":{
          "a":"total pressure is not equal to static pressure",
          "b":"total pressure is equal to static pressure",
          "c":"0",
          "d":"infinity"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"b",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
      },
      {
        "question":"An aircraft is flying at cruise level with a velocity of 110m/s at an altitude of 10 km and the dynamic pressure is 5.43kN/m2. Now assume the aircraft is flying is at sea level with a speed of 65m/s and the same dynamic pressure. In the above data, the velocity 65m/s refers to __________",
        "answers":{
          "a":"true air speed",
          "b":"equivalent airspeed",
          "c":"free stream velocity",
          "d":"cruising speed"
        },
        "correctAnswer":"b",
        "difficulty":"beginner"
        },{
          "question":"Pitot tube with flat faces are more sensitive.",
          "answers":{
            "a":"True",
            "b":"False"
            
          },
          "correctAnswer":"b",
          "difficulty":"beginner"
        }
    
    ]
  }